Jake Brawer

PERSONAL DATA

Ph.D.: 3rd Year

Website: http://jakebrawer.com/ Email: jake.brawer@yale.edu

Github: https://github.com/JakeBrawer

RESEARCH OVERVIEW

Summary I build human-robot collaborative systems that learn through their interac-

tions with people. My research draws upon recent innovations in machine learning as well as foundational techniques in artificial intelligence for designing systems

that learn and reason in a transparent and robust way.

EDUCATION

2016-Current Ph.D. in Computer Science

Yale University, Advisor: Brian Scassellati

2012-2016 B.A. in Cognitive Science; Computer Science minor

Vassar College

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2016-Current Robotics Ph.D. student -Social robotics laboratory, Yale University Human-

robot collaboration research under the supervision of Professor Brian Scassellati.

2014-2015 **Research Fellow** –Interdisciplinary robotics research lab, *Vassar College* Designed and programmed a genotype-phenotype mapping scheme for mobile behavior-

based robots incorporating sexual reproduction and ontogenetic factors.

2014 Neuroscience researcher – Icahn School of Medicine, *Mount Sinai* Conducted fMRI research on resting state networks in macaque monkeys. Acquired skills

using fMRI analysis software FSL.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Spring 2018 Intelligent Robotics

Teaching Assistant

Fall 2017 Object Oriented Programming

Teaching Assistant

Fall 2014, Fall Perception and Action

2015

Teaching Assistant

TECHNICAL AND SCIENTIFIC SKILLS

Research Human-robot collaboration, natural language understanding

Programming Python (and scientific tools), C-C++, Rust, LATEX, Git, Jekyll, Emacs, Con-

tinuous integration (with Travis)

ML/AI General machine learning and computer vision techniques

Robots Robot operating system (ROS), 2+ years experience with Baxter research robot

System 4+ years of daily **Linux** experience

GRANTS

March 2018 Bridging the Gap: An NSF Workshop on Conversational Agents and

Human–Robot Interaction

Justine Cassell, Brian Scassellati, Jake Brawer, Michael Madaio

NSF Cyber-Human Systems (CHS), Robust Intelligence, National Robotics Initia-

tive. Award #1829237

SERVICE

 ${\bf Conference \quad International \ Conference \ on \ Humanoid \ Robots \ ({\bf Humanoids}; \ 2018)}$

reviews International Conference on Human–Robot Interaction (HRI; 2017)

Journal ACM Transactions on Human–Robot Interaction (THRI; 2019)

reviews

Students Acshi Haggenmiller (2016-2017) supervised Sarah Widder (2017-Current)

Tan Zong Xuan (2017-2018)

Kevin Choi (2018)

Conference proceedings

Brawer, Jake, Olivier Mangin, Alessandro Roncone, Sarah Widder, and Brian Scassellati (2018). "Situated Human-Robot Collaboration: predicting intent from grounded natural language". In: *Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*. URL: https://jakebrawer.vip/assets/pdfs/IROS18.pdf.

Scassellati, Brian, Jake Brawer, Katherine Tsui, Setareh Nasihati Gilani, Melissa Malzkuhn, Barbara Manini, Adam Stone, Geo Kartheiser, Arcangelo Merla, Ari Shapiro, et al. (2018). "Teaching Language to Deaf Infants with a Robot and a Virtual Human". In: *Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*. ACM, p. 553. URL: https://jakebrawer.vip/assets/pdfs/CHI18.pdf.

JOURNAL ARTICLES

Brawer, Jake, Aaron Hill, Ken Livingston, Eric Aaron, Joshua Bongard, and John H Long Jr (2017). "Epigenetic Operators and the evolution of Physically embodied robots". In: Frontiers in Robotics and AI 4, p. 1. URL: https://jakebrawer.vip/assets/pdfs/FRONTIERS17.pdf.